## MÓNICA LEIRAS

Digital Marketer



## PROFILE

I'm a resourceful and creative digital marketing professional specializing in brand marketing, digital advertising, and growth marketing.

With a Master's Degree in Innovation and Technological Entrepreneurship, I began my career by co-founding a startup and later worked as a marketing manager in a creative agency, more recently managing a B2C brand.

My entrepreneurial and professional path has built up my tenacity, resilience, and growth mindset, and I thrive in developing, executing, and optimizing marketing initiatives.

## CONTACT



#### **Phone**

(351) 926 647 341



#### **Email**

monicarafaelaleiras@gmail.com



#### Address

Pedrouços, Maia - Portugal



#### Web

www.monicaleiras.com



#### LinkedIn

/monicaleiras



## Skype ID

live:monicaleiras.mr

## EXPERIENCE

#### JUN 2018 - PRESENT

#### **CREATIVE MANAGER MARKETER** @ CREATIVE 70NF

In this creative Marketing agency, I am responsible for managing the digital marketing channels of several clients in the Healthcare and Textile sectors. In 2019, I assumed the role of lead brand manager of Bedattitude, a B2C E-Commerce platform pertaining to Creative Zone. Here, I create, execute, analyze and optimize marketing campaigns, which include lead generation, digital advertising, email marketing, and marketing analytics.

#### FEB 2017 - FEB 2018

#### **CO-FOUNDER & CONTENT MANAGER** @ FRAMIE

I co-founded this startup and had a key role in its bootstrapping phase, including customer discovery, go-to-market strategy, product launch, and growth marketing. I also led content management and had constant contact and iterations with end-users with the goal of optimizing their experience.

## DEC 2014 - JUN 2018

#### WEB DEVELOPER & MARKETER @ MITIC

Upon challenging myself to learn front-end development (WordPress), I co-started this freelance collective and greatly improved my skillset by assuming projects with customers in Advertising, Government, E-Commerce, and Textiles.

## EDUCATION

#### SET 2015 - OUT 2017

# MASTER'S IN INNOVATION AND TECHNOLOGICAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP @ FEUP & FEP

In this Master's degree, I acquired and evolved a series of competencies focusing on startup and business development. These included marketing, finance, business strategy, product marketing, and business intelligence.

## SET 2012 - JUL 2015

#### **BACHELOR'S IN BIOLOGY** @ ECUM

With a fundamental education in the various domains of Biology, I developed technical skills in Biotechnology, Genetics, and Ecology, partaking in different research and industrial projects.

## LANGUAGES







## **PROJECTS**

#### > MAR - OUT 2017

# MASTER THESIS "MOBILE USER ENGAGEMENT: NEW APPS VS MAINSTREAM APPS"

My dissertation focused on strategies for technological companies to reduce user churn and improve the profitability and loyalty of end-users.

#### > OUT 2016 - MAR 2018

#### **PINKIT - ONLINE STORE**

Leveraging my skills in front-end developing, startup bootstrapping and digital marketing, I started this E-Commerce project (women's accessories store) to improve my analytical

## ACTIVITIES

#### > WEB SUMMIT 2017

**ALPHA STARTUP** 

I participated in the Alpha Startups program as Framie's Co-Founder and I took this opportunity to improve my networking skills.

#### > UNIVERSITY STARTUP WORLD CUP

PORTUGAL FINAL & DENMARK SEMI-FINAL

I partook with the Framie team as we won the Portuguese competition and took part in the International semi-final.

## > STARTUP PORTO ACCELERATOR 2017

ANJE & INFSCTEC

During this 6-month acceleration program, I expanded my startup development and networking skills.

## MANAGEMENT IN LOCAL & UNIVERSITY GROUPS

I had the experience of managing different teams and organizing events.

#### > COURSES

I continuously seek to update and expand my know-how by taking courses in the Google Marketing Platform, SEO, and social media management.

#### > VOLUNTARY WORK

Social responsibility has always been a must for me, and I actively collaborate with local and national associations, both in communication and organizing activities.

#### > SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

I explored my passion for music by directing, training, and playing the organ in a local choir and my passion for acting by being a part of a local theatre group.

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

DIGITAL MARKETING

GROWTH MARKETING

BRAND MANAGEMENT

MARKET RESEARCH

MARKETING ANALYTICS

WEB & GRAPHIC DESIGN

FRONT-END WEB
DEVELOPMENT

## TOOLS

FACEBOOK ADS

FACEBOOK ADS

GOOGLE ANALYTICS

WORDPRESS

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

ADOBE INDESIGN

GOOGLE DATA STUDIO

SOCIAL MEDIA MGMT.
SOFTWARE

EMAIL MARKETING
PI ATFORMS

## PERSONAL SKILLS

CREATIVITY TEAM WORK

ADAPTABILITY PROACTIVITY

COMMUNICATION TENACITY

MANAGEMENT & RESOURCEFULNESS ORGANIZATION